<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Ernesto Matos</title><link>https://ernestocid.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Ernesto Matos</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ernestocid.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://ernestocid.github.io/projects/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 14:45:02 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://ernestocid.github.io/projects/</guid><description>Bellow you will find some of the projects I created.
BETA: stands for B basEd Testing Approach. It is a tool-supported approach, based on the B-Method formal notation, to generate test cases. It uses restrictions described on a B model, such as invariants, preconditions and conditional statements, to create unit tests for an operation. You can read more about BETA on my Ph.D thesis, in some of the papers here and in the tool&amp;rsquo;s website.</description></item><item><title>My First Post</title><link>https://ernestocid.github.io/blog/my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 17:31:02 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://ernestocid.github.io/blog/my-first-post/</guid><description>Hello world!</description></item><item><title>Publications and Presentations</title><link>https://ernestocid.github.io/publications/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ernestocid.github.io/publications/</guid><description>Presentations Simplifying Asynchronous Service Communication with Kafka, Debezium and the Outbox Pattern at Kafka Summit Americas, 2021. Publications Bellow you will find a list of my published papers and other academic work. If you are interested in more information about my academic profile, visit my Lattes page.
Matos, E. C. B.; Moreira, A. M.; Souza Neto, J. B.. An empirical study of test generation with BETA. In: Journal of the Brazilian Computer Society, Volume 22.</description></item><item><title>Reading</title><link>https://ernestocid.github.io/reading/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ernestocid.github.io/reading/</guid><description>Here is a list of books that I&amp;rsquo;ve read and that I usually recommend to people:
Debugging Teams: Better Productivity Through Collaboration by Brian W. Fitzpatrick and Ben Collins-Sussman.
Radical Candor: Be a Kick-Ass Boss Without Losing Your Humanity by Kim Scott.
Managing Humans: Biting and Humorous Tales of a Software Engineering Manager by Michael Lopp.
The Pragmatic Programmer: From Journeyman to Master by Andrew Hunt and David Thomas.</description></item><item><title>Now</title><link>https://ernestocid.github.io/now/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ernestocid.github.io/now/</guid><description>This is what I&amp;rsquo;m doing now.
I&amp;rsquo;m living in São Paulo and working at Loggi.</description></item></channel></rss>